本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
妈
Mom.
咋啦
What?
你在干什么呀
What are you doing?
流点儿汗  锻炼一下心肌功能
Squeezing in my cardio, working up a sweat.
那很好  您能不能把汗流到PJ的三明治上
Okay. Well, can you sweat on P.J.'s sandwich?
我要燃烧了
Gotta feel the burn.
我要自己去买午餐了
Gotta buy my lunch!
嘿  亲爱的  亲爱的
Hey, honey. Honey!
咋啦
What?
我要去上班了
I'm leaving for work.
过来亲我一下让我走吧
come on, Give me a kiss.
想亲就来抓我呀
Catch me if you can.
反正也亲得够多了  又不差这一次
I've kissed you enough already.
看来这还真的是真理
Wow, I guess it's true:
一日三餐中早餐最让人操心了
Breakfast is the most disturbing meal of the day.
等等  喂  喂  喂  鲍伯
Wait. Whoa whoa whoa. Bob, wait.
有件事忘了跟你讲
I forgot to tell you something.
是你那梅尔叔叔  他之前打过电话
It's about your Uncle Mel... he called.
我可不想听这个
I don't wanna hear it.
听听看嘛  他求我给你传个话来着
Oh, come on! He begged me to pass on the message.
那谢谢你  风很大  听不见
Thank you, and now I'm going to pass on the message.
梅尔叔叔是谁啊
Who's Uncle Mel?
一个你永远不会认识的人
Somebody you'll never know.
他是你爸的叔叔
He's your father's uncle.
得了  你连那个古怪的斯坦利叔叔
Okay, so you told me about Uncle Stanley
给他家小猫织毛衣的事都告诉我了
Who knits sweaters for his cats,
却仍然不能告诉我谁是梅尔大叔吗
But you didn't want to tell me about Uncle Mel?
因为啊  泰迪  要是你对一个人的评价
Because, Teddy, if you don't have
没有任何一句好话时
Anything nice to say about someone,
那还是对他一字不提的好
Then don't say anything at all.
再说梅尔他就是个大傻子
And Mel's an idiot.
好了  妈妈  快跟我讲讲这个梅尔大叔
Okay, mom, tell me about Uncle Mel.
是这样的  他跟你爸
Well, he and your father had
有一段不堪回首的过去  这是我仅知道的
Some kind of falling out. That's all I know.
难道我们就没有办法搞清楚吗
Isn't there some way we can find out more?
这可是自从啥时候开始  有关老爸唯一的囧事呢
This is the first interesting thing about dad since...
好了  其实根本就是老爸这辈子唯一有趣的事儿
Well, this is the first interesting thing about dad.
宝贝  相信我吧  我可是有过前车之鉴的
Honey, trust me. I've learned the hard way:
看到任何有关邓肯家的家庭伦理八点档
When it comes to Duncan family drama,
躲远点吧
Stay out.
那咱家还有没有其他什么意外惊喜的亲戚
Are there any other Surprise relatives
你想要讲给我听的啊
you want to tell me about?
没啊
No.
真的没
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
生活搞得一团糟
Today's all burnt toast
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
Running late, and dad jokes
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
Has anybody seen my left shoe
■
翻译： 山鹰逢羽
我闭上双眼  咬口早餐
I close my eyes, take a bite
跳上车子  放声大笑
Grab a ride, laugh out loud
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
There it is up on the roof
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
I've been there, I've survived
所以听取我的建议
So just take my advice
■
校订  后期： WaitinZ
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, baby,
世界有很多疯狂无奈
Things are crazy
可是我知道你会有美好未来
But I know your future is bright
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, Baby
不要怀疑
There is no maybe
一切终会如你所愿
Eveything turns out all right
生活有悲有喜
Sure life is up and down
可是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
But trust me, it comes back all around
你会喜欢将来的你
You're gonna love who you turn out to be
宝贝  不要放弃
Hang in there, Baby
查莉成长日记  第一季第十集
Good Luck Charlie  S01E10  Take Mel Out to the Ballgame
大好消息  妈妈  我现在开始喜欢小查莉啦
Great news, mom. I like Charlie now.
是么  总算有这天啊  发生什么事了
Well, finally. What happened?
我们刚才在公园  遇到一个摄影师
We were in the park and this photographer
他认为咱家小查莉是他见过的最可爱的宝宝呢
Thought that Charlie was the cutest baby ever.
他说要付一百块请查莉当模特
He offered to pay her 100 dollars to use her as a model.
天知道  除了会吐口水和拉便便之外
Who knew? She's actually good for something
她还真的也有自己的强项呢
Besides drooling and pooping.
沃尔特·鲁珀摄影工作室
"Walter Louper photography.
专门从事犬类猫类以及婴儿照相
Specializing in dogs, cats and babies."
没门儿  我可不会用我家宝宝去赚钱的
Forget it. I'm not exploiting my baby.
可我们又没有狗或猫
But we don't have a dog or a cat.
妈妈  考虑下吧
Mom, come on.
这可能是查莉的绝佳星途的开始呀
This could be a big break for Charlie.
PJ  查莉不会在你之前先去赚钱养家的
P.J., Charlie is not getting a job before you do.
我也想  可是那摄影师没有说要来给我拍照呀
Well, the photographer didn't offer to shoot me.
哈  你又不是非得去做模特才算有工作的
Ha. You don't have to have a modeling job.
什么活都能赚钱的  过来妈妈这里吧
Any job will do. Come here.
哼  这种谈话最后总会变成数落我的不是
Man, this conversation sure took an ugly turn.
不管咋样  我们都用不着这张名片了
Anyway, we will not be needing this.
我早知道应该按着我的主张来办
I knew we should've done it my way.
你的主张是啥
What was your way?
我们不要告诉老妈去拍照的事
We don't tell mom we're doing the photo shoot,
直接去拍了然后把钱分赃了事
We go ahead and do it anyway and split the money.
你什么时候想出这主意的
When did you come up with that?
就在公园里啊
At the park.
我是在那些女子越野队经过的时候告诉你的
I told you when The girls' cross-country team ran by.
哦  想起来了
Oh, yeah!
我们当时说了些啥
What were we talking about again?
嗨  小查莉  泰迪姐在这儿呢
Hi, Charlie. Teddy here.
看来有一个邓肯家族的神秘人浮出水面啦
So it turns out there's a Duncan family mystery.
是的  昨天我发现咱家有一位梅尔大叔
Yeah, yesterday I found out we have an Uncle Mel.
我戴这个好看不
Does this look good on me?
这个嘛  除非你把裤子套到脸上试试
Well, only if you pull your pants over your face,
因为这根本就是条腰带
because that is a belt.
我们今天得去一下商场
We need to go to the mall today.
你这儿都没什么新衣物可以给我穿了
You don't have anything new for me to wear.
好了  艾薇  我现在考虑的是
Okay, Ivy, I'm thinking about something
比衣服要重要一点的事
a little bit more important than clothes.
鞋子吗
Shoes?
是家族啦
Family.
你真会搞笑  小泰
You're funny, T.
听着  我爸跟他的梅尔叔叔闹不和
Okay, listen. Something went down between my dad and his Uncle Mel
而我就必须搞清楚这中间到底发生了什么事
And I have to know what happened.
这是什么
What is this?
哦  这是之前我爸给我的信用卡
Oh, that's a credit card my dad gave me a while ago.
居然到现在我才听说这件事
And I'm just now hearing about this?
好啦  那个只是为了以防万一的
Well, it's for emergencies only.
亲爱的  我检查过你的衣柜了
Honey, I've seen your closet.
现在正是紧急状态
It is an emergency.
好吧  如果你陪我去养老院
Okay. Well, if you go to the rest home with me,
那我就陪你去商场
I will go to the mall with you.
可以  不过我要先警告你
Okay, but I have to warn you:
我爷爷就在养老院
My grandpa was in a rest home
那情况可碜人了  他就成天坐在那儿
And it was depressing. He'd just sit there
抱怨为什么从来没有人去看他
And complain about how nobody ever came to visit.
最后我终于受不了  再也不去了
Finally, I just stopped going.
我们荫园疗养院提供好几种计划可供选择
We have several options at Shady Hills:
有一年计划  三年计划  还有五
There's the one-year plan, the three-year plan and the fi...
令尊多大年纪了
How old is your father?
那也许你可以选择按月续费的
You might want to go month to month.
好的  再见
Okay. Bye-bye.
欢迎光临荫园疗养院  有什么可以效劳
Welcome to Shady Hills. How can I help you?
我们来看望梅尔·邓肯
We're here to see Mel Duncan.
你们预约登记了吗
Have you signed in?
没有啊
No.
那你们是在等待一份正式邀请函吗
Are you waiting for a formal invitation?
没有  我们刚到这儿  很愿意先登记一下
No, we just got here.We're happy to sign in.
很荣幸  请吧
I'd be most honored.
我给你们呼叫梅尔过来
Let me page Mel for you.
梅尔  你有一个访客
Mel, you have a visitor!
居然有人来看我啊
Somebody here to see me?
你好  梅尔叔公
Hi, Uncle Mel.
我是你的侄孙女泰迪  是鲍伯的女儿
I'm your great-niece Teddy. I'm Bob's daughter.
没开玩笑吧  鲍伯生得出这样漂亮的女儿
You're kidding. Bob made you?
哦  是啊  我妈很靓的
Yeah, well, my mom's pretty hot.
哦  这是我的朋友艾薇
Oh, this is my friend Ivy.
你好  我老妈也很靓
Hi. My mom's hot too.
好吧
Okay.
喂  乡亲们  看看我的侄孙女
Hey, everybody, this is my niece...
你刚才说你叫啥名字来着
What did you say your name was again?
我叫泰迪
Teddy
哦  是海蒂
...Hedy.
（注：引发特洛伊战争的希腊美女）
不不  是泰迪  泰迪
No no, Teddy. Teddy.
真是个奇怪的名字
That's a weird name.
不比海蒂奇怪吧
Weirder than hedy?
这是我的侄孙女泰迪
This is my niece Teddy
那么  你喜欢音乐吗
And... do you like music?
我很爱音乐啊
I love music.
嘿  乡亲们  我的侄孙女要给大家唱几首歌
Hey, everybody, my niece is gonna sing us some songs.
我要唱吗
I am?
对的
Yeah
艾薇  快帮忙
Ivy, help.
嗨  各位父老乡亲
Hi, everybody.
欢迎来到
And welcome to...
来到这个我们现在呆着的房间现场
The room that we're in.
首先  我们开场先来点
We're gonna start off with a little...
大师你说呢
Maestro?
我觉得我还会弹弹《故乡亲人》
I think I remember "Swanee River."
那就《故乡亲人》吧
"Swanee River."
沿着斯旺尼河而下
Way down upon the Swanee River
旅程多么遥远
far far away...
我不记得歌词了
I don't remember the words.
自从三年级后我就没弹过正经的曲子
I only know the dirty ones from third grade.
这条河的名字真是有趣呀
It's such a funny name for a river
是我唯一能给的评语了  嘿嘿
And that's all I have to say, hey.
好了  这首唱够了  我们唱点别的吧
Okay, that's enough of that. Let's try something else.
有要点歌吗
Any requests?
《故乡亲人》
"Swanee River."
哎哟  天哪
Oh, boy.
差不多都准备好了
It's almost ready to go.
你们家的宝宝真是可爱
You've got a real cute baby there,
是我见过的最棒的之一
One of the best I've ever seen.
是啊是啊  你倒是带足现金没
Yeah yeah, did you bring the cash?
我带了  但我需要一个家长在这授权书上签名
I did, but first I need a parent to sign this release form.
没问题
No problemo.
问题来了
Problemo.
当然了  老妈就在厨房呢
Sure. Mom is right in the kitchen.
她在吗
She is?
她在的啊
She is.
盖比  不如你到厨房去
Gabe, why don't you go into the kitchen
让妈妈给我们签个名
And have mom sign this for us?
那么您是一位专业摄影师啰
So you're a photographer, huh?
是呀
Yup.
我十七岁生日的时候也得到了一个相机
Oh, I got a camera for my seventh birthday...
后来我把它丢了
Then I lost it.
好感人的小故事
Cute story.
好了  这个给你
Well, here you go.
你妈妈的字体还真  不错啊
Your mom has very nice... Printing.
我看  在我们开始拍摄前
You know, before we start the session
我最好还是亲自去和她谈一谈
I probably better go talk to her.
相当不好的计划
Very bad idea.
那是为什么
And why is that?
因为她现在情绪不佳
Because she's in one of her moods
她现在想要更高的价了
And now she wants more money.
是吗  她要价多少啊
She does? How much?
一百二十五块
125 dollars.
什么
What?
可我们说好是一百块的
But we agreed on 100 dollars.
我跟这种大起大伏的
Walter, I've been riding
情绪波动相处已经十七年了
this rollercoaster for the past 17 years.
就让我来处理吧
Let me handle it.
这次状况真古怪
This is a strange situation.
一般那些宝宝的妈妈们总是很渴望跟我见面的
The moms almost always want to meet me.
这家的妈妈只想要钱而已
This one just wants her money.
收拾走人吧  表演结束了
Pack it up. The show's over.
啥  怎么回事啊
What? What happened?
她想要你滚蛋
She wants you out.
你不明白  我很赶时间的
You don't understand. I have a deadline to meet.
我们必须赶紧弄完这事
We have to make this work.
那好  也许你可以付她一百五十块
Well, you might want to offer her 150 dollars.
好吧  一百五就一百五  不过这是底线了
Fine. 150 dollars, but that's it.
我再去说说情好了
Let me see what I can do.
咱们可以开始变戏法啦
Let's make some magic.
我小妹妹的名字是查莉
And my baby sister's name is Charlie.
又是查理又是泰迪的
Charlie, Teddy...
难道你爹连一个姑娘的名字都取不出来吗
Didn't your dad know any girl names?
说到我老爸啊
Speaking of my dad,
你们俩之间到底发生了什么事呢
What exactly happened between you guys?
你可不会想听那种老八股的
You don't want to hear about that.
其实我很想听的
Actually, I do.
你看啊  我们才刚见面
Well, look. We just met
我个人比较希望先多了解一下别人
And I'd like to get to know someone
然后才能跟对方说他老爸的坏话
Before I start saying bad things about their father.
那好吧  我们就来加深彼此了解吧
Okay. Well, let's get to know each other.
跟我说说你自己吧
Tell me about yourself.
嗯  我热爱棒球
Well, I love baseball.
对了  今天有场比赛啊  你能带我去不
Hey, there's a game today. Will you take me?
跟我说说你的别的事好了
Tell me other things about yourself.
哎呀  求你了  我都很久没去看过什么球赛了
Oh, come on. I haven't been to a ballgame in forever.
我可以用任何代价跟你交换
I'd give anything to go to one.
你说今天就去哦
Well, today?
我不知道啊  我已经答应我朋友去
I don't know. I promised my friend...
知道了  知道了  算了吧  谢谢
yeah yeah, fine, thanks.
多谢你顺便来我这里逛
Thanks for dropping by.
二十年后再见吧  反正我会一直坐在这里的
See you in 20 years. I'll be sitting right here.
小泰  你一定要尝尝这个
T. You've got to try this.
这是啥
What is it?
牛扒加土豆
Steak and potatoes.
这地方的人能把世间万物都榨成汁
They can blend anything in this place.
好吧  艾薇  听着
Okay, Ivy. Hey.
你说咱们来给计划小小变动一下怎么样
What would you say to a little change in plans?
我会喜欢这种变动吗
Am I gonna like this change?
变动计划中包括我们赶紧离开这地方
It involves us getting out of here.
我加入
I'm in.
我们要去看场球赛
We're going to a ballgame.
那我退出
I'm out.
那好  那就继续留在这里
Fine, then stay here.
重新加入了
Back in.
梅尔  来吧  我们出发了
Mel, come on, let's go.
我们要去看球赛啦
We're going to the ballgame.
去吃热狗  太棒了
Hot dog! Sounds great,
不过首先我们要过看护那一关
But first we've got to get past the warden.
我去搞定她
I'll handle her.
劳驾  我想申请今天下午带梅尔出去转转
Excuse me. I'd like to take Mel out for the afternoon.
你满十八岁了没
Are you over 18 years of age?
没有
No.
他死了没
Is he dead?
没啊
No.
请求不予批准
Request denied.
别挡在桌子前面
Step away from the desk.
谢谢您的宝贵时间
Thank you for your time.
B计划
Plan B.
- 很好  - 行动
- Right. - Break.
很抱歉  大爷
I'm sorry, dude.
但这是为了日行一善
It's for a good cause.
有个人滑出去了
We've got a roller!
在我眼皮底下绝不允许
Not on my watch we don't.
你玩得开心吗  梅尔叔公
You having a good time, Uncle Mel?
再棒不过了
The best.
哦  真是太精彩了  孩子
Oh, this is terrific, kid.
谢谢你带我来
Thanks for bringing me.
客气
Yeah.
那你看  之前你说过只要我们来看比赛
So listen. You said when we got to the game
你就会告诉我关于  喔
You were going to tell me the story about... whoo!
你和我爸之间的故事
...What happened between you and dad.
过了这局再说
After this inning.
又烫又辣的  大家让让
Hot stuff coming through.
艾薇  艾薇  你这买的都是些什么
Ivy! Ivy, what is all this?
谁让你要把信用卡给我保管的
It's your fault for giving me a credit card.
对啊  那是应急信用卡
Right. The emergency credit card.
这些东西有的是可以应急的呀
Some of this stuff could be used in an emergency.
是哦  除非我们会掉到一个巨大的泡沫鼻子里
Right, like if we run into a giant foam nose.
看来他玩得很开心
It looks like he's having fun.
是啊  多亲切的老人家啊
yeah Such a sweet old guy.
有谁会跟他闹不和呢
Who could possibly have a problem with him?
你这臭手
You stink!
你算是球手还是跳芭蕾舞的啊
Are you a ballplayer or a ballerina?!
我看到你就想吐
You make me want to puke!
超超超巨星呀
<i>Su-su-superstar</i>
她是大明星  遥不可及
<i>She's a star, going far</i>
这就是你啊  超级巨星
<i>There you are, su-su-superstar</i>
超级明星  跳起来吧
<i>Su-su-superstar, yeah, come on</i>
从早到晚  完美行头  贵妇装扮
<i>Looks all right, ladylike, day and night</i>
来吧  超级巨星
<i>Come on, su-su-superstar</i>
超级巨星啊
<i>Su-su-superstar</i>
一周七天  环球巡演
<i>Grooving the runway from Monday through Sunday</i>
她出书上杂志  人们疯迷她
<i>She wrote the book, got the look, on every magazine, love her</i>
超级巨星  超级巨星  你天生就是啊
<i>Superstar, superstar, that's what you are</i>
超超超级巨星  耶  一个超巨星呀
<i>Su-su-superstar, yeah, a superstar</i>
耶  你生来就是超巨星呀
<i>Yeah, a superstar, that's what you are</i>
超级巨星啊
<i>Su-su-superstar.</i>
小心点  软脚虾  滑垒的时候当心脏了你的裙子
Careful, cupcake! If you slide, you might dirty your skirt!
嘿  梅尔叔公  冷静点  我们领先着呢
Hey, Uncle Mel, calm down. We're winning.
是啊  暂时的  但不会维持多久
Yeah, for now, but it ain't gonna last.
因为他们臭死了  就像阴沟里的垃圾
Because they stink! Like a sewer, they stink!
喂  管好你家老爷子  他把我孩子都吓着了
Hey, control your grandpa! He's scaring my kids.
喂  你家小孩是垃圾
Hey, your kids stink.
对不起  他不是那个意思
Sorry. He didn't mean that.
我敢肯定你家小孩闻着可香了
I'm sure your kids smell awesome.
好了  梅尔叔公  不如我们好好坐下来吧
Okay, Uncle Mel, why don't you just sit down
吃根好吃又安分的热狗怎么样
And enjoy a nice, quiet hot dog?
我爱吃热狗  喂  臭肠子  吃我一根香肠
I'd love a hot dog. Hey, weiner, have a weiner!
不要
No!
你到底管不管他  不然我就自己动手了
Are you gonna do something about him or should I?
好了  我说过我会自己处理的
Yeah, I said I'd handle it and it would be
只要你不多管闲事就容易的多
a lot easier without your helpful suggestions.
好啊  我现在来管管闲事
Oh, well, here's a helpful suggestion:
把他带出场  不然我就要赶你们出去了
Take him out of here or I take you out of here.
哦  你会后悔说了那句话的
Oh, you shouldn't have said that,
因为现在艾薇女王要出动了
'cause now Ivy's about to get out of her chair.
小泰  拿着我的戒指
T, hold my ring.
好了  我们就不能淡定些吗
Okay, can we all just chill?
喂  落水狗们  好好瞧瞧这个
Hey, losers! Get a load of this!
不要啊
No!
天啊  我们上大屏幕了
Oh no, we're on the jumbo screen.
我们快照完了吧
Are we almost done?
因为再不结束的话  我们就要超时了
'cause if not, we're kinda getting into overtime.
那有什么问题吗
Is that a problem?
不是我们说了算
Not for us.
不过老妈那边不好过关  她会多算你钱的
But for mom. I think it's gonna cost you.
跟我想的一样  小弟
Exactly what I was thinking, little brother.
我要去跟老板汇报一下
I'm gonna run this by the boss
老妈  你干嘛来的
Mom. What are you doing here?
我住这里的
I live here.
但你现在本不该回来的啊
But you're not supposed to be back yet.
是啊  我提早把事情做完了  我洗好了车
Well, I finished everything I needed to do... got the car washed,
去买完杂货  又去了银行
Did the grocery shopping, went to the bank.
客厅里的闪光是怎么回事
What is that flashing coming from the living room?
也许只是保险丝烧了  你大概应该去检查一下
Oh, it's probably a fuse.You might want to check
车库里的电路盒
The fuse box out in the garage.
快出去  别拍了
Get out! Shut it down!
出什么事
What's going on?
老妈在家了  她现在真的在家了
Mom's home. She's really home.
快出去
Get out!
这里在搞什么鬼
What's going on here?
PJ  你想要接这招不
P.J, you want to take that one?
不了  我还是接下一招好了
No, I'll take the next one.
我不敢相信你们对我阳奉阴违
I can't believe you two disobeyed me.
哦  我可怜的小宝贝
Oh, my poor little baby.
我喜欢这画面  母女天伦
I love it... mom and baby.
听着  别拍了  赶紧走吧
Look. Please stop. Just get out.
但你俩在一起看上去美极了
But you look so good together.
不  我说真的  出去
No, seriously... get out.
很好  就像那样
Perfect. Just like that.
像这样吗
Like that?
对
Yes.
那再这样偏一下头怎么样
And how about a little of this?
很好
Great.
等等  拍我这半边更好看
Wait. Get my better side.
哇  老妈  你真是天生做明星的料
Wow. Mom, you're a natural.
就是  镜头感很好啊
Yeah, the camera loves you.
你们两个小子绝对是要被关禁闭了
You two are so grounded.
之后警察很客气地把我们请出去了
Then the police politely asked us to leave,
就在那时梅尔叔公邀请他们一起去亲吻
At which point Uncle Mel invited them to kiss something
（注：美国职棒大联盟比赛不成文约定
当大屏幕转到观众席 被照到的相邻两人必须亲吻）
因为大家当时都被大屏幕照着呢
That had been on the jumbo screen.
呃  不错  行了
Oh, good. All right.
现在你知道我为什么要叫你们离梅尔叔公远点了吧
Now you know why I wanted you to stay away from your Uncle Mel.
那家伙是个疯子  特别是到棒球比赛场的时候
The guy's a maniac, especially when it comes to baseball.
是啊  我记住这条了
Yeah, that would've been useful information.
好了  赶快去睡觉吧
You know what? Just go to bed.
我真是不想再继续这个话题了
I really don't want to talk about this anymore.
好吧  不过还有一件事
Well, there is one more thing
是跟梅尔叔公有关的
I should tell you about Uncle Mel.
又来  什么事啊
Yeah? What's that?
他就在客厅呢
He's in the living room.
什么
What?!
你必须和他谈谈
You have to talk to him.
不  我不要  不要  我跟他没什么好说的
No, I don't. I don't. I've got nothing to say to him.
这中间到底有什么曲折啊  为什么没人告诉我
What is this all about, anyway? Why won't anybody tell me?
因为是陈年的历史了
Because it's ancient history.
行吧  都过去了  大家都快忘了
All right? It's done.It's forgotten about.
我已经不介怀了  现在赶紧把那老屁虫赶出我的房子去
I've moved on. Now get that old fart out of my house!
我马上回来
Be right back.
爸爸说欢迎你来
So dad says welcome.
他不想跟我说话  对不对
He doesn't want to talk to me, does he?
好得很  我也不想跟他说话
Well, I don't want to talk to him either!
你可以告诉他  这是我说的
And you can tell him I said that.
去去就回
I'll be right back.
梅尔叔公说他爱您
Uncle Mel says he loves you.
真的吗
Really?
梅尔大叔能说这话
Uncle Mel said that?
对呀  他说的差不多就是这意思
Yeah, he said something like that.
离我到客厅去时都过去那么久了
It's so long since I've been in the living room.
好吧  他到底什么时候才能离开客厅
Well, when is he gonna leave the living room?
够了  梅尔叔公想彻底解决这件事
Okay, Uncle Mel wants to sort this thing out.
也许你应该先开口啊
Maybe you should start.
我觉得他才应该先让步
I think he should start.
那我去去就回
I'll be right back.
老爸说他爱您
Dad says he loves you.
废话
Hogwash!
而且他觉得也许应该
And he thinks it would help
由你来告诉我这场宿怨的由来
if you told me what this feud was about.
你爸十岁的时候  我是他的棒球教练
When your father was 10 years old, I was his baseball coach.
喔  现在我明白了
Oh. Now I get it.
你那恍然大悟是啥意思
What's that supposed to mean?
好吧  我觉得您对于棒球是有点太激动太执着了
Well, you get a little bit too excited about baseball.
我有话就直说
I share my opinions!
不管怎样  我给了他一些很有建设性的意见
Anyway, I gave him some constructive criticism...
你说我挥杆像个娘们儿
You said I swung like a girl!
我那已经是好话了  其实你挥杆就像个小宝宝
I was sugar-coating it! You swung like a baby girl!
嘿嘿  大家开始谈话啦  这是个好的开始
Hey, we're talking. This is a start.
你在全队面前羞辱我
You humiliated me in front sof the entire team.
我是想要帮你提升自己
I was trying to make you better.
那你怎么从来不对其他的孩子吼
Well, you didn't yell at any of the other kids.
因为我根本不关心其他的孩子啊  痴呆儿
Because I didn't care about any of the other kids, fathead!
哇  你听到没
Whoa. Did you hear that?
在他骂你痴呆之前
Before the fathead part.
他说他其实最在乎你了
He said he cared about you.
我想让你变得更坚强
I was trying to make you tough
我猜
And I guess
有时候我是太激动了
sometimes I got a little carried away.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我方得到一个道歉耶  嘿  老爸看你的
We have an apology. Hey, dad.
呃  也许我有时候也确实太敏感了
Well, maybe sometimes I was a little oversensitive...
我也抱歉了
And I'm sorry.
人家还你一个道歉啦
And a return apology.
现在你晓得我们家在吵架之后会做什么吗
Now you know what we do in this family after we fight?
我希望是大吃一顿
I'm hoping eat.
我们会拥抱彼此
We hug.
抱抱是娘们儿风气
Hugging's for girls.
小娘们儿
Baby girls.
那真是
That's...
我要去嘘嘘
I gotta tinkle.
大概二十分钟后回来
Be back in 20 minutes.
就在那边
Right over there.
过来
Come here.
你做得很好  孩子  谢谢你
You did good, kid. Thank you.
是吧  你们大家老是说什么
Yeah, well,you guys are always saying
家庭有多么的重要之类的
how important family is.
是啊  是啊  确实很重要
Yes. Yes, it is.
他是不是走到储物间里面去了
He just walked into the'?
我怕是的
I'm afraid so.
喂  梅尔  那边不是洗手间
Hey, Mel, That's not a bathroom.
现在是了
It is now!
好啦  小查莉  现在我在这儿等你和妈妈呢
Well, Charlie, here I am waiting for you and mom,
因为老妈说我一定要看看这个  不管是什么
'cause mom said I have to see this, whatever this is.
我们来啦
Here we come.
哎呀  看你们两个美的
Look at you two!
你们为什么穿成这样啊
Why are you dressed like that?
呃  因为我们有个角色通告
Well, we had a casting.
是专业模特事业
In the professional modeling business,
这个就叫做试镜了
That's what an audition is called...
一个通告
A casting.
那你俩现在算是专业模特了吗
So you're a professional model now?
哦  别表现的太惊奇  泰迪
Oh, don't act surprised, Teddy.
我想大家都知道这一天迟早会到来的
I think we all knew this day was coming.
她现在是模特了
She's a model now.
如果我早知道赡养父母会这么难的话
If I knew raising parents was gonna be this hard,
我一定会缩手不干的
Never would've done it.
不过很快就会轮到你的责任了
But soon enough it'll be your turn
祝你好运啰  查莉
So good luck, Charlie.
四十年后
我是PJ·邓肯  来探望我家老头老太太
P.J. Duncan, here to see my parents.
嘿  妈妈
Hey, mom!
我马上就好  PJ
I'll be right with you, P.J.
我正上课到一半呢  我们正要做推力运动
I'm in the middle of class. We're really gonna push it.
这次一定要碰到脚趾
We're gonna touch our toes.
好  现在来摸脚趾头
And touch your toes.
或是摸到膝盖也行
Or your knees.
知道吗  只要尽力而为就行了
You know what? Just do the best you can.
好的  现在我们来做下蹲
Okay, now we're gonna squat.
好  蹲下  感觉到燃烧了吗
Oh, take it down! Gotta feel the burn.
就像这样
Here we go.
哦  不
Oh, no!
鲍伯  我又僵住了
Bob, I'm locked again.
鲍伯
Bob!
唱《故乡亲人》
"Swanee River"!
来吧  妈妈  我来扶你
Here, mom. I gotcha.
哦  谢谢你  PJ
Oh, thank you, P.J.
哦  对不起我来迟了  家人们
Oh, sorry I'm late, guys.
从停车场走过来还真是好长的路啊
That was a long walk in from the parking lot.
这就是不常常做下蹲的后果
That's what happens when you don't do the squats.